microdirect.co.uk 2013-12-26

# Security & Privacy Policy - microdirect.co.uk

### Website security

Microdirect is committed to respecting your privacy. In general, you can visit our website without giving any personal information. Some information is required in order to process orders or send latest offers through our newsletter. All of this information is collected in secure mode. A padlock sign shown at bottom right of your screen help you identify secure mode.   

In secure mode all your information is transferred to our secure server using industry standard "secure socket layer". We also use McAfee secure to keep you safe from identity theft, credit card fraud, spyware, spam, viruses and online scams. We do these checks on daily basis to make sure there is no compromise to security.   

As stated in our privacy policy, we've taken the appropriate measures to ensure that your personal information is not unlawfully processed. We tread data as an asset which must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. Microdirect.co.uk uses industry standard practices to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal identifiable information, including "firewalls" and Secure Socket Layers.

## Privacy Policy

Micro Direct is committed to respecting your privacy. In general, you can visit Micro Direct without revealing any information about yourself. We do collect information regarding visitors to our website. Some information is required in order to process orders, for example, we analyze this data for trends and statistics to help us provide you with a better service.

To process your order, we require your name, billing address, phone number, email address and credit card details. Credit card information can be removed after purchasing an item by clicking on the icon “manage credit cards” and click the box with the cross. If we need to contact you via email first hand. If unsuccessful (or time is critical), we will try to contact you by phone.

Any information provided by you will be used for Micro Direct purposes only. However, Micro Direct may need to provide your name and delivery address to third parties that are involved in the processing of your order uses for delivering specific services to you (for example, the financial institution that issued your credit card or the courier that delivers your order).

Your information will not be shared with individual or other companies (such as direct mail organizations or other third parties) unless required by law.

There are times when we may request information from you, such as your, name, address and e-mail address. When additional information is requested, we will try to let you know at the time of collection how we intend to use the personal information you provide, such as respond to your inquiry, accept an order, conduct a survey or allow you to access specific information such as account information, etc. We do our best to maintain the accuracy of any personal information you do supply to us.

You can help Micro Direct update and maintain the accuracy of any personal information you supply by using the account profile pages or notifying Micro Direct of any changes to your address, title, phone number or e-mail address.

Cookie Information  
Cookies are small bits of text used by a browser to store information on your computer’s hard drive. Each cookie can only be read by the web server that originally issued it. Cookies cannot profile your system or collect information from your hard drive. Most On-Line retailers use cookies.

Micro Direct uses Cookies to let us know you are a prior customer and thus you will not need to re-enter certain information every time you shop at the site. We do not use cookies to store credit card numbers, address information or any other personal information.
